[eerie music playing]
-[dramatic drumbeat]
-[percussive whirring]
[soft squelching]
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
[distorted splashing]
[eerie music building]
-[gurgling]
-[music fades]
[suspenseful piano music playing]
[foghorn blares]
You're my first catch in days. but
you're too little.
Whoa. look what's coming.
That one looks nasty.
Yeah. it does.
I better get home before it hits.
-See you tomorrow.
-So long.
[thunder crashing]
[woman] Everyone remembers where they were
the day the rain came.
[car beeps]
It was a Sunday. not quite winter.
The forecast had called for sun.
[man 1 on radio] This low-pressure system
offshore has turned
and is moving in fast.
[man 2] Expect periods of
heavy rain showers across the city today.
with winds gusting up to 30 miles per hour
and the threat
of minor coastal flooding and high surf.
[man 3] The holidays are a month away.
and hopefully.
the surprise turn in the weather will...
[woman] People went
about their mornings as usual.
-Ready?
-Yeah. let's do it.
[woman] We lived
close to each other then...
Okay. bye.
[woman] ...but it was easy to feel alone.
Guys. come on. It's gonna rain.
Yeah. let's go inside.
[thunder crashing]
[woman] The day the rain came.
we learned
we were not alone.
[man on radio] Last December
was the warmest on record
for western Washington.
so keep tuned in for updates.
[clattering]
Come on. Come on.
[woman] And we learned
just how far some will go
to protect their home.
[sloshing]
[beeping]
[dog whining]
Hey. where is everybody?
Where is everybody?
There's my old boy.
Good morning.
[woman sighs]
-I can't believe the kids let me sleep in.
-Was wondering why it was so quiet.
You caught us breakfast?
Oh yeah. Big catch this morning.
World's best fisherman.
-I know.
-Thank you.
-Good morning.
-Wake up!
-Donuts!
-Whoa!
-[girl] Donuts!
-[boy] Gimme.
-[girl] Can we make bacon?
-[man] Just calm down. Just... Come on.
-[boy] Bacon!
-[woman] Please leave some for us!
-[man] Vultures.
-Total vultures.
-[girl] Turn it on!
-Okay.
-[girl] Make it work.
[woman] I just gave Cassidy his meds.
and don't feed him any bacon.
You deserve it more than they do.
[energetic game music playing]
[device bleeps]
-Dad. the streaming stopped working.
-[rain pattering]
I don't know. I think
this house is really falling apart.
-I'm ready to move when you are.
-Sure.
A few more lottery tickets
and we should be good to go.
Hey.
You know I'm just kidding. right?
This isn't all on you.
Oh. the guy is coming tomorrow
to check the cracks in the chimney.
Mm.
-[scoffs] This is new.
-What?
He thinks our foundation is sinking.
so the only thing
holding the house together is the chimney.
The house collapsing on us
while we're sleeping would be a bummer.
Do you still wanna go buy
a Christmas tree?
-It's raining out there.
-Come on.
Wait. wait. Dad. come on.
You promised. Please.
-[softly] I didn't promise. You promised.
-[kids] Dad!
-You promised.
-[boy] Dad!
-Who promised you guys?
-[both] You!
[chuckles]
-Yeah. let's go.
-Come on.
Let's buy a tree.
-[boy] Let's go!
-[girl] I wanna pick!
-Help me put my shoes on.
-You know how to put your shoes on.
Hey. no scooter in the house.
Come on. Mom! Let's go!
-She always takes forever.
-Then you shouldn't act surprised. right?
Help your sister put her shoes on.
Go wait in the car.
Ann! Let's go!
-Don't rush me.
-I'm not.
I'm hiding from our children.
Seriously. when can we stop doing
this tree thing?
It's Christmas. you Grinch.
[groaning]
Okay. what did you do?
You have to unlock it. stupid.
-I did. stupid!
-Shut up!
[man] Stop arguing! You're both stupid.
[girl] It won't open because of Graham.
-[Graham] Don't blame me. That was you.
-[girl] You obviously did something!
No. I didn't.
Why do you blame me all the time?
[tense music playing]
[girl] It's all your fault!
This is why I'm the favorite.
and you always cause problems.
-[Graham] Shut up. You're such a baby.
-[girl] I'm not a baby!
I'm 8 years old!
[tense music building]
What did you two do?
-[both] Nothing!
-[girl] Ugh!
[Cassidy whines. barks]
-[man] Quiet. Cass.
-[Cassidy continues barking]
[Ann] Okay. Cass. shush.
Guys. Why aren't you in the car?
-Door won't open.
-Can't get out.
We've tried every door. Nothing will open.
-You guys. Guys.
-I'll try the windows in my room.
[Cassidy whining]
What? [chuckles] Okay.
[music becomes stirring]
[Cassidy barking]
[scoffs]
[Ann] This is absurd.
[lights plinking. buzzing]
Yeah. It's a prank. Teenagers.
They glued all the windows and doors shut
or something. right?
No prank. Quiet. Cass!
[Ann] But I don't have any service.
Not connected. No Wi-Fi.
[Ann] Unplug the router
and plug it back in. D'you try that?
-Did you pay the bill?
-[man] Yes.
[Ann] Cass. quiet!
Do you have signal now?
-No. nothing.
-[girl] Mom. Dad.
I tried the windows in my room.
Nothing's working.
-It's like it's glued shut.
-Every window in there is stuck.
-[Ann] Cass!
-[Cassidy continues barking]
[tense string music building]
-[girl] Dad!
-[Graham] Dad.
Are you okay?
-[Graham & Ann] Are you okay?
-Yeah.
Yeah. I'm fine.
[music fades]
-I'm fine.
-[Ann] Okay.
[girl] What is going... Dad!
-I don't understand.
-Okay. stand back.
-Why? Wait. What are you talking about?
-[girl] Dad!
-No. no!
-Stand back. I'll take care of this.
[Ann] Jason. no!
[Cassidy continues barking]
-Just stop!
-Mom!
-[Ann] Stop!
-[girl] Dad!
[tense string music building]
[dramatic drums pounding]
Mom.
Dad.
[Jason grunting]
Kids.
Dad. look!
-[music fades out]
-[Cassidy stops barking]
-Oh my God.
-[Jason] It's not just us.
-Hey. we can't get out.
-Look. someone's coming.
[Ann] Yeah.
[Jason] That's what's-her-name
from across the street.
-Greg's wife.
-Whatever her name is.
-[Ann] Susan.
-[Jason] Susan!
Susan. go get help!
We're stuck in here! Go get help!
-[Ann] He can't get out either.
-I'll be right back.
Okay. okay. good. She's gonna go get help.
-She's gonna go get help.
-[Jason] Yeah.
Great. It's okay.
-So we're fine.
-[Jason] Okay. Yeah. I know.
It's... I...
It's okay.
[Jason] Yeah. it's okay. Yeah.
-[foreboding orchestral music playing]
-[metallic banging]
[Jason grunts]
[panting]
[birds tweeting]
[music fades out]
Okay. guys. let's see
what the neighbors are up to.
-You know all the neighbors?
-Pretty much.
Yeah. so the Richardsons are
across the street.
They have three grandchildren.
and I think Max is a dentist.
[Jason] Yeah. That's what's-his-name.
-Bike boy.
-[Graham] Hmm?
-Bike boy?
One of those guys
who wears all that dumb gear.
It's Greg. His wife was the one
who ran to go get help.
Why isn't she back yet?
[Ann] Don't worry. I'm sure
she'll be back with the police soon.
Then there's that nosy guy down there.
Oof.
-What's his name?
-Oh my God.
Do you know anyone's name here
on this street?
Yeah. this annoying lady with the dog.
Who else?
Oh. yeah. Let's not forget
doofus with the boat.
What was it called?
"Seas the Day"?
Such a doofus.
[girl giggling]
-Good job.
-Mm-hmm.
-Ann.
-Mm?
"This was a one-night stand. LOL."
Oh no!
What's a one-night stand?
-Um...
-It's an adult sleepover.
What's the difference
between an adult sleepover
and a regular sleepover?
Uh... Well. in an adult sleepover...
-You can have as much candy as you want.
-[girl] That sounds fun.
[Jason] I guess so. I don't know.
[curious music playing]
"Government?"
[girl] Hey!
That took a long time.
No. it didn't.
"Maybe. But why?"
"For our safety?"
Oh. look. Doofus with the boat has a sign.
Is that how you spell aliens?
No. honey. it's not.
Why would aliens wanna lock us all
in our houses?
[Ann] They wouldn't. honey.
[Jason] "The whole world?"
[Cassidy grumbles]
[rain pattering]
-Okay. everybody. look at me.
-[music fades out]
We are safe. We are in our home.
We have everything we need here.
but most importantly. we have each other.
-Can I have a donut?
-No. Eat your spaghetti.
But I wanna stress eat.
How do you know about stress eating. Ruth?
[Ann] Graham.
If you can make it in there.
I can make it out here.
Do you think
the running woman has found help?
Someone's gonna come. I promise.
I think it was the rain.
The rain did this.
No. baby. it's just rain.
-We'll be fine. I promise.
-[long ethereal notes droning]
[Ruth] The rain looked different today.
[Ann] I'm trying to keep it together
for the kids.
But what the hell's going on. Jason?
How is this real? Like. honestly. how?
-I don't know.
-Oh my God. My parents.
They must be freaking out right now.
The Richardsons across the street?
They're okay. right?
I'm sure your parents are okay too.
You're right.
[chilling chords droning]
I need to show you something.
[Ann] Is that a gun?
Jason. you can't buy a gun
and not tell me.
-I was going to tell you.
-What about the kids?
I know.
-Okay. I've been having this nightmare.
-What? What nightmare?
I woke up a couple weeks ago.
and I felt this thing.
I just... I... I felt we weren't safe.
And you feel safe now?
-I'm sorry.
-Okay.
Okay?
Okay.
Show me how to use the stupid thing
before you put it back.
[car alarm beeping]
[key clicking]
Oh. come on.
-[key clicking]
-Come on.
Good one. idiot.
[low whirring]
[whirring continues]
[squelching]
What the hell is this?
[Ann] Hey.
I can't break through.
The rain is creating some kind of barrier
around the house.
The same thing going down.
[Ann] Who's doing this?
I don't know. but they've sealed us in.
Are we gonna have to worry
about running out of air?
I checked that too.
Air is getting in.
Okay. Then we wait for the rain to stop.
Come to bed.
Ann.
Whatever is keeping us in here is not...
man-made.
[Ann] Please hide this from the kids.
[creaking]
[music fades out]
[rain pattering]
[distant bird cawing]
[birds tweeting]
[Jason] Mm.
[gentle music playing]
I already tried it.
[music fades out]
You two seem pretty calm about this.
There's nothing
we could really do about it. right?
Yeah. You guys are the parents.
You'll figure this out.
[curious string music playing]
[Jason] Great. Move that a little. Yeah.
All right. It's time for you guys
to start learning about good music.
You're telling me this is good music?
Yeah. The classics.
Oh. we have a DVD.
Huh.
I guess we have two movies only.
Okay. so now your mom
is gonna talk to you guys about chores.
Okay. look. this isn't a vacation.
You're gonna keep a schedule.
You're gonna make your beds.
You're gonna get dressed every day.
You're gonna brush your teeth.
[Ruth] Cass!
[Jason] We need to focus
on the essentials.
If we ration carefully.
there's no reason
our food can't last us two months.
-Is that food?
-Yes.
I think these are really old.
[Jason] Maybe even longer.
Yeah. we'll eat those last.
As of right now. we still have power.
we have water.
we have gas. but there's no telling
how long any of that's gonna last.
So we have to start treating water
and power as luxuries
that we could lose at any moment.
Hey. this is all temporary.
and we're gonna get through this.
Your mom and I will keep you safe.
I promise.
Team Delgado on three.
-I don't think we need to do this.
-Just do it.
[Ann] One. two. three.
[all] Team Delgado!
-Can I have a donut now?
-No.
[Cassidy whining]
Oh.
Cass.
Old man.
I can't open this door. okay?
I'm so sorry.
Just pick anywhere you like.
I'll clean it up for you.
Ru.
What did I say?
We act like we're at school
during school time.
Dad. I've already done this chapter.
-Do it again.
-What's the point of it?
Might sound like a waste of time now.
Graham. but you...
But you're right.
It's a total waste of time.
[Jason sighs]
[groans softly]
Okay. You guys wanna learn something real?
-Something you might actually use one day?
-Yeah.
Let's go.
Are you ready?
Today. you guys are gonna learn
how to gut a fish.
Obviously. we don't have any fish.
but Ruth here. she was kind enough
to donate three of her stuffies
for this lesson.
-Please.
-You're welcome.
Thank you very much.
Now. what are the rules with knives?
Don't cut your fingers off.
-Don't stab your brother.
-What?
Don't stab anyone.
All right. so first thing you're gonna do.
you're gonna cut off
the head and the tail.
You're not gonna eat those parts.
With the head off. you're gonna find
a very convenient hole right here.
at the base of the throat.
And that's where
we're gonna start our incision.
and this will also ensure
that we don't rupture any organ
that can contaminate our meat.
Slice down the middle like this.
and then you start scooping out the guts.
If this was a real fish.
we would wash it out in water.
We could use a faucet. or even better.
we would wash it in the ocean.
How do you know so much about fish?
Because I love the sea.
and I had my own fishing boat.
-Really?
-Mm-hmm.
-Where is it?
-I sold it.
-Why?
-Because kids are expensive.
[Graham] Mm?
Dad. [chuckles]
[Jason chuckles]
Now. open up your fish. and that's
where we're gonna find your fillets.
and that's the part we're gonna eat.
What are you guys doing?
Gutting fish.
Mine's a mermaid.
I see that.
So we're at the "let the kids play
with knives" phase of this.
-Uh... they're learning.
-[Ruth] Yeah.
And we're being careful. Mom.
-And we're having fun.
-Having fun.
Mm.
Mm-hmm.
I wanna know how far this has spread.
Can you ask neighbor farther down?
Exactly. like a game of telephone.
So. what time do you
usually start drinking around here?
-Uh. 11:00?
-Uh-huh.
More like 10:30.
Oh no. It's been doing that.
That's exciting.
[Ann] No.
Whoa. whoa. whoa. whoa!
No. don't throw that away.
-What you doing?
-I'm saving this.
-Oh.
-Yeah.
This goes over here like this.
Lay it in here.
And once it dries.
then we have tomato seeds.
-What?
-I love you.
I know. 'cause I'm amazing.
Yes. you are.
[hopeful string music playing]
[Jason] Five blocks. Everyone the same.
Thanks. Max.
"How are you?"
So far. so good. You?
"Getting by."
"What do you do for a living. Jason?"
I'm an engineer. Max.
Currently unemployed.
[chuckles] Yeah.
My kids have some cavities.
Can you come over and fix 'em?
Do you have any food?
Enough for now.
You?
[sighs]
Okay.
[music fades]
[sloshing]
[ominous flute music playing]
[chuckles]
We don't draw on the windows. Ruth.
[Jason] Hey. hey. hey. hey. hey!
[drumbeat playing]
-You.
-[Ann] Uh-oh.
Mom? Can you go?
No. it's all you. girl.
[Ann] Do I have to?
-You have to.
-[Ann] Yes. you have to.
-You have to. you have to. Come on.
-[funky bass line kicks in]
Come on.
Here. Put your foot here.
-["Close To Me" by The Cure playing]
-♪ I've waited hours for this ♪
♪ I've made myself so sick ♪
-♪ I wish I'd stayed... ♪
-[Jason] Come on.
♪ Asleep today ♪
♪ I never thought this day would end ♪
♪ I never thought tonight could ever be ♪
♪ This close to me-hee ♪
♪ Ba-ba-ba-ba. ba-dum ♪
♪ Ba-ba-ba-ba. ba-dum... ♪
No scooters in the house. Come on. I...
♪ Just try to see in the dark ♪
♪ Just try to make it work ♪
♪ To feel the fear ♪
♪ Before you're here ♪
♪ I make the shapes come much too close ♪
♪ I pull my eyes out
Hold my breath and wait... ♪
It comes all the way
from this part here. and then it goes...
Three. four. five.
♪ Safe and clean... ♪
♪ Oh. if only I was sure ♪
♪ That my head on the door was
A dre-ee-eam... ♪
-Uno. I win!
-Two of the exact same card?
♪ Mm-hmm ♪
♪ Doo-doo-doo ♪
♪ Doo-doo-doo... ♪
[Ann] Final demand?
[inaudible]
[laughter]
-Okay. ready? One. two. three.
-[cheering]
The perfect tree!
Guys. look. Neighbors.
Oh. it's so pretty.
Christmas.
[song ends]
[thunder rumbling]
[eerie creaking]
[rain pattering]
-She's back.
-Who's back?
The rain walker.
You're so dumb.
[unsettling piano music playing]
[Ruth] She visits when it rains.
[distant growling]
I told you.
Shut up.
It's...
it's probably just an animal.
Not a lot of salad in this salad.
If you don't want it. I'll eat it.
We'll have more vegetables soon.
It just takes some time to grow.
-Can I please have cereal this one time?
-No.
This is what we're eating.
Don't get to be picky right now.
-I'm not hungry.
-Me neither.
Okay. then you don't eat.
I saw someone outside today.
-Graham saw her too.
-Just the rain. She's lying.
-I'm not.
-You are.
-I'm not!
-Just please just stop.
I think that sometimes. if you stare
out the window for long enough.
you see a lot of things
that aren't really there.
I saw her. Mama. I did.
I think she's trying to communicate.
You didn't communicate with anyone outside
because everybody else is locked inside.
Sorry.
Ru. sorry for raising my voice.
but now is not the time for stories. okay?
Okay. Can we try and stay
a little bit more positive?
-Yes.
-Yeah.
I have a surprise.
I made us Christmas cookies.
We ran out of sugar.
so I had to improvise.
They probably taste really bad.
Thank you. I'm sure they taste great.
-Thanks.
-You're welcome.
-Thank you.
-You want another one?
I don't think so.
[chuckling]
[Jason] God!
Oh. this is one weird Christmas.
Yeah. we're not screwing them up. are we?
This is gonna scar them for life.
We are doing the best we can for them.
That's what matters.
-And that's what they'll remember.
-Yeah. you're right.
This will be a distant memory one day.
and our kids are super resilient.
Do you wanna get high
and watch Air Force One?
[blows raspberry. exhales]
I'm sorry. what?
I found one joint
at the bottom of our sex drawer.
We have a sex drawer?
What do you call the place
we hide the lube and toys we got...
-Ah.
-one time for Valentine's Day?
Yeah.
-Yeah.
-I guess we have a sex drawer.
Wave. Blow it up the chimney.
[giggling]
-She heard that?
-Just snuck in.
"I'll do anything to save my family."
"Don't ask me for something I can't give."
Can you not quote the movie
before it starts? You know I hate that.
-Yeah.
-[industrial music playing on TV]
"Get off my plane!"
Why do you know this movie?
It's... I... It's a classic. Ann.
Or I could put Annie on if you want.
No!
-No. Please. no.
-Well.
I just need one night
without hearing those songs.
Air Force One. it is.
[dramatic drumbeat]
[Jason] So many stars.
[Ann] The skies clear up real quick
when no one's using the world.
[Jason] Yeah. no airplanes.
no helicopters. no pollution.
[soft string music playing]
We don't have to worry
about paying our mortgage this month.
Hell yeah.
This is as good as date nights
are gonna be for a while.
You like this.
Oh yeah. I love this.
No. this.
This.
It's like you're. in a weird way.
happier in here with us.
In a weird way.
I am.
Just... just a little bit.
[Ann chuckles]
No way!
[Jason] Whoa.
[Ann] Oh my...
She's beautiful. [gasps]
Big girl.
[high-pitched barking]
Good luck out there.
It's her world now.
We are no longer the ones
steering this ship.
[animals chattering]
[Ruth] Mom! Dad! Quick!
Santa came!
-[Jason] What you got there?
-[Ruth] Half an apple.
[Jason] Half an apple?
[Graham] I already have this one.
We were sort of hoping that you'd forget.
What is this?
Maybe you could use it
for a pretend hair salon.
-Thanks.
-Okay.
This is for both of you. Whoa. whoa. whoa!
[Ruth] Piano books?
Yeah. you know.
the piano that your grandma got you
that's just been collecting dust.
-But I don't wanna play piano.
-Okay.
-Graham?
-No.
-We tried.
-Awesome.
Yeah. Gray. find a present for Mom.
What? What did you get me?
You guys. thank you.
It's your very first tomato.
They saw it growing in the kitchen.
and they wanted to surprise you.
-You grew it. Mama.
-[Ann] Oh my gosh.
That's so sweet.
Should I cut it so we can share it?
-You can eat it all by yourself.
-Yeah. go ahead and eat your tomato.
[wondrous music playing]
It's really good.
-I'm crying.
-Yeah.
Mama! The old lady needs help!
Mrs. Richardson. Take them to the den.
-Dad.
-Let's go.
What's happening? Dad?
-[Ruth] Dad! No!
-Let's go. Come. Let's go. Go.
[climactic string music playing]
[music fades]
Is she gonna be okay?
No. honey. She was not okay.
[Ruth sobbing]
Is Christmas over yet?
Yeah.
[thunder crashing]
[sighs]
That's the last of it.
Sorry. Cass.
Just hold it together for me.
[rain pattering]
[Ruth humming]
♪ Rain. rain. go away ♪
♪ Come again another day ♪
-[Cassidy whining]
-[Ruth] Don't worry. Cass.
[humming]
[eerie music playing]
[thunderclap]
[jarring high-pitched whining]
♪ Rain. rain. go ♪
-[screaming]
-Please help me!
[chilling music playing]
-[screaming]
-What? What?
There's a person outside. There she is!
-What's wrong?
-Stay away from the window.
[Ann] Why?
[Cassidy barking]
[woman yelling]
Mom! Dad!
-[Jason] Who is that?
-[woman] They're dead.
-[Jason] It's the neighbor.
-[yelling]
They're dead. Everyone is dead!
Don't let them see you!
It's over.
They're here. and no help is coming.
-Susan.
-No help is coming!
-We can't help you. I'm sorry.
-[Susan] Help me!
You must... help!
Hide.
[screaming]
-[wet growling]
-[Susan screaming]
[deep rumbling]
[roaring crash]
[rumbling and roaring subside abruptly]
Okay. family meeting. Right now.
[Cassidy whining]
-I don't know what I'm looking at.
-I've tried to tell you.
But the one I saw seemed nice.
Just... not like the ones tonight.
Whatever we saw out there.
whatever is keeping us in here.
it's... it's not nice.
Listen to me.
I'm not gonna let anything bad
happen to us.
[ominous orchestral music playing]
Can we sleep in your room tonight?
Yeah.
Let's limit
all signs of life visible from outside.
-We start covering up all the windows.
-Especially when it's raining.
Are monsters real?
They are now.
Not helpful. Gray.
Sh.
Let's settle down. okay?
Okay. Mama.
Sh. Go to bed.
What do we do?
We survive.
[creaking]
-[Cassidy barks]
-Cassie? No. Drop it. Cassie!
Hey! Hey.
You know what?
You can play with Cassie later.
Right now. let's do some PE time.
Mom. Dad wants us to do PE. again.
[stirring string music playing]
[creaking]
[clanging]
[both] Dad!
I think it's the chimney cap.
It must have fallen out.
Yeah. you can see all the way through now.
[Ann] Can you see the cracks?
Are they getting bigger?
Cracks?
Why do we have cracks in our chimney?
'Cause our house has structural damage.
Does that mean the house is
gonna fall on us?
-I hope not.
-No.
[Ruth] Guys. who cares?
Maybe we can get out now
through the chimney.
It's way too narrow at the top. My weight
would make the whole thing collapse. baby.
Then how does Santa get down the chimney?
[giggles] Guys. I'm kidding.
Let me try going up.
I'm the lightest.
so you can hoist me with my silks.
[mysterious music playing]
I'll be fine.
Step on it.
[Ann] Nice and slow. okay?
-[Ruth] Bye. guys!
-[Ann] No.
Oh God.
Okay. I don't like this.
Wait. I can see the cracks!
Don't touch them. Don't touch anything.
You were right. Dad.
I could never get through here.
[Jason] Baby.
I'm gonna bring you down. okay?
Wait! I wanna try something.
[Ann] Just please be careful. okay?
Careful! Slow down.
[hopeful string music playing]
[Ruth] My hand's outside the house!
My hand's outside the house!
My hand is outside the house!
Mom. the weather's changing.
I can feel the air and everything.
Okay. that's enough.
Come down. Okay. bring her down now.
-[Jason] Careful. careful.
-[Ann] Come on. come on.
Take it slow. There we go.
Almost there.
Oh my gosh.
-Good job. Are you okay?
-Yeah.
Oh. my brave girl. I'm so proud of you.
[Cassidy whining]
What's with Cassidy?
No.
[Cassidy whining]
Oh no.
[Jason] Cass.
-[Ann] No. don't move him.
-[Jason] Sorry. Cass.
-Oh. my Cass.
-[Jason] It's his heart.
-[Ann] Aww.
-[Jason] The medicine ran out.
He had a really good life. you guys.
-Why are you saying it like that?
-Because he's really old. honey.
And sometimes when you get really old.
you can get very sick.
[softly] Get the kids back to the den.
Put the TV on.
[Ann] Okay. you guys. come on.
Let's go watch Annie in the den.
[Ruth] But. Mom.
I wanna stay with Cassidy.
[Ann] I know.
-[mournful string music playing]
-[labored breathing]
♪ So you've gotta
hang on till tomorrow... ♪
[volume increasing]
I know it's loud.
Cover your ears. Let's sing.
♪ Tomorrow. tomorrow ♪
♪ I love you ♪
[mournful string music continues]
[Cassidy whining]
-♪ You're only a day... ♪
-[gunshot]
♪ Away ♪
You did the right thing.
Yeah.
I have a problem now.
He can't just stay here.
The fireplace.
Like. the... a cremation.
after the kids fall asleep?
Yeah. it's an option.
-But there is also the freezer.
-No. we're not doing that.
If things get bad.
like. really. really bad...
we might wish we had that option.
I need you to handle it.
And I don't wanna know anything about it.
[sinister string music droning]
[door closes]
[Ruth sobbing]
Okay. It's okay.
[stirring string melody playing]
Yeah. Yeah. come on.
It's all right. You can take it.
-Yeah.
-[thunderclap]
[music fades out]
[low rumbling]
[Ruth] What if doofus is right?
Maybe they are aliens.
Aliens can't control the rain.
You don't know that.
[Graham sighs deeply]
Whatever they are...
we're their prisoners now.
Why would they lock us inside forever?
Why?
Maybe to punish us.
[Ruth] Guess that's all the sunlight
you get today.
[haunting piano music playing]
-Rain. Let's go.
-I got the den.
Let's go. You know the drill.
[music becomes sinister]
Let's go. Ru. Go.
Ruth. come on.
-Hey. what is this?
-What?
-What's your problem?
-Okay. enough.
Hey. don't do that.
-[Ann] Enough.
-Don't do that.
Okay. Come on.
My plant.
-Hey. Hey.
-[Ruth] Get off.
[Jason] What are you doing?
[growling]
[gasps]
[roaring]
Don't!
[low growl]
[eerie music playing]
[wet growling]
[clattering]
[whimpers]
I just wanted to...
It's okay. Hey. it's okay. It's gone.
It's okay. You did good. You did good.
You all did real good.
I'm still hungry.
-We're rationing.
-[mumbled] I know. but I gotta eat.
-So do I.
-Here.
-Have the rest of mine.
-No!
I want more than that.
Just for tonight. please!
I'll go back to starving tomorrow.
Stop it! Stop it right now!
-Move!
-We're all hungry.
-Let me see!
-I'm hungry too.
Let me see in there. then I'll know.
-I said no.
-Let her see.
[scoffs]
You wanna see it too? Fine.
[Ann panting]
[muffled] Mom! What's happening?
[muffled] She's fine. She's just...
[somber music playing]
[muffled sobbing]
[muffled yelling]
[Jason] Okay.
This is going to end one day.
We'll survive this.
No.
It's not time for that anymore.
It's time to be honest.
-We're gonna starve.
-No. Stop.
-Yes.
-No. don't say that.
I refuse to watch our babies die.
I'm not having this conversation with you.
This is happening.
No. we'll live.
We'll do better than that. We'll thrive.
I'll figure this out.
Trust me.
No. You won't.
It's over.
[Jason sniffles]
[Graham] Mom. Dad.
You could cook these.
-Did I clean them wrong?
-No. you didn't do anything wrong. baby.
Come here.
[gentle music playing]
Come here. You didn't do anything.
[wolf yelps]
[thunder crashing]
[sinister music building]
[music becomes stirring]
Where are you going?
Pull.
[Graham] What happens next?
Now we wait.
Sh. Sh.
[softly] Yes. Go on. grab it.
Yeah.
Go. go. Oh.
[groans]
It's okay. It's all right. [panting]
Pull!
[fox screeching]
[fox whimpering]
[exhales deeply]
Oh no. No. no. no.
You should give it to the kids.
You're cloudy headed.
You haven't eaten in days.
Just eat and then go back to work.
[music turns stirring]
Foxes eat carrots?
This isn't for the fox.
[stirring music building]
[squirrel screeching]
What's wrong?
[music peaks. fades out]
[squirrel chirps. screeches]
Chimney fishing.
[tender piano music playing]
-[Ann] Watch out. it's hot.
-[Jason] Okay. go ahead.
[all laughing]
So. here. I need all of this pulled up.
[Jason] Once you get
beneath the underlayment and the subfloor.
you're gonna get. like. a few inches
of soil and gonna hit the barrier.
I'll make it work.
[optimistic orchestral music playing]
[woman] Days blurred into weeks.
weeks into months.
People had no way of knowing
how long the visitors would be here.
so they hid themselves to stay safe.
Most people starved and died.
Others lost hope and gave up.
Still others found purpose and kept on.
[insects chirping. buzzing]
The lucky ones found togetherness.
I need more fertilizer.
Damn. you know. I'm fresh out.
We could make our own.
What do you think?
I thought it was pretty good.
Pretty good.
[laughter]
[Jason] Come on!
I need more light.
[woman] The outside world
had become strange and dangerous.
Inside. people found
what they needed to survive.
Inside. they were free.
[thrilling music playing on TV]
-How did they lose the gun?
-Yeah. I don't know. baby.
Ah! Ah!
-Get off my plane!
-[all] Get off my plane!
[Jason] Yeah! Whoo!
-Yeah!
-Whoo!
Yeah!
-[Ruth] What?
-[Graham] No!
[Ruth] Aw!
[Jason] We knew
this would happen eventually. right?
Yeah. but there can still be music.
[plays notes softly]
[piano notes playing slowly]
[wistful music playing]
[Ruth] Morning.
[bears grunting]
[birds tweeting]
[insects chirping]
[thunder rumbles]
[fox whines]
[Ruth] Hello. rain.
Right on time.
[thunder rumbles]
What will it be for you today. sir?
The usual. fade? Side and back?
Oh. I didn't realize
you were entertaining.
Hey. Graham.
You ready for your next haircut?
[birds tweeting]
Wow. what's that?
I hooked up the trap to be automatic.
[skunk chittering]
-So no more fishing.
-That's not real fishing. Ann.
Aren't we growing enough food now
to stop using the traps?
[skunk screeching]
[creaking]
[ominous string music playing]
[clattering]
[metallic clang]
[growling]
[music stops]
-[door closes]
-[Jason] Ann?
Hey. Ann?
-[Ann] The house is definitely sinking.
-[Jason] House is sinking.
That's great. That's. uh... lovely.
I wanna show you something.
Okay. no. look. It's getting worse.
Okay? The soil is eroding under the house.
Yeah. five years of daily rain
will do that. Come on.
It's like whatever's keeping us locked in
is the thing keeping the house together.
I say just let it all fall apart.
Maybe one day
we'll be all... living in an invisible box.
and that can be kinda cool.
Call the kids. I wanna show you something.
[engine revving]
[Ann] What?!
[Jason] What you gotta say
about that. huh?
-What?!
-[Jason] Come on.
-Oh my God.
-[engine revs]
-You hear that?
-[Ann] Yeah.
-Yeah?
-[Ann] Yeah. I do.
Nothing a little elbow grease
can't accomplish. am I right?
Yeah. Yeah.
Only got enough gas
to turn it on a few times.
-[Ann] Mm-hmm.
-She really runs.
Right?
I mean. come on.
-[Jason] Yeah.
-How many years?
-Yeah. six.
-Seven.
-Seven years!
-Give or take.
Yeah. yeah. it's a lot of work.
Yeah. do you see this?
[Ann] Oh my God.
Yeah. a lot of work.
-It's a waste of time.
-What?
[uneasy string music playing]
What'd you... what'd you say?
No. it...
You built a car
that'll never drive anywhere. you know.
so what would you call it?
If you wanna work on something useful.
you can help me put
the dew collector up tomorrow.
Why? We already have all the food
and water that we need.
We can't rely on that forever. Can we?
You tell me. Can we rely on that?
Power's gone. Gas is gone.
Everything is gone.
But we are still here.
We are still here.
I'm here. You're here.
Your sister is here. Your mom is here.
We survive because I fight for us.
And if one day. Graham. this rain stops.
you bet I'm gonna be ready for it.
Are you done showing us your stupid car?
Yeah. Gray. I'm done.
[Ruth] Graham. come on. wait.
Graham. wait.
[Ann] Graham's getting worse.
They're both getting worse.
This is not a childhood.
You think
I don't think about these things?
You never talk about them.
I have one job here.
One job only.
which is to keep all of you guys alive.
We are all in here with you too.
This is not just your problem
for you to fix.
The kids miss their father.
And I miss my husband.
[rain pattering]
[Jason] It's time to help
with the water collection.
Shut the curtains. Let's go.
[pump squeaking]
Everybody's getting too lax
with the rules. especially you.
-What?
-[Jason] Yeah.
We're too exposed from your drawings
in the attic. and that has to end.
No. no. no.
You can't just take that from me.
-I can.
-Are you kidding?
-One mistake only...
-Mom?
And we risk losing everything.
How long can we keep hiding?
-Just...
-What's the point?
[growling]
[gurgling]
[softly] Hide. hide. hide. hide!
[Ann] Okay.
[tense string music playing]
[softly] Go. go. go.
[wind howls]
[creaking]
[creature growling. clicking wetly]
[softly] Sh.
[creature squelching]
[squelching]
[growling]
[creature roars]
[screeching]
[snarling]
[Ann. softly] Jason.
The gun. Gun.
[creature grunting]
I'll go.
No. Stay there.
Stay there.
[growling]
[creaking]
[wind howling]
Ah!
[tense music building]
[Ann] Graham! Graham! No!
[Graham] What are you doing?
Dad. what are you doing?
Stop! Stop! Stop!
I almost got out. I almost made it out.
-I almost made it.
-Okay.
-I could've...
-[Ann] You okay?
That's salt water.
What? Hey.
-You okay? No. wait.
-It's seawater.
What?
Come here. away from the window.
Hey. hey. you guys hear that?
The rain stopped.
[solemn chords droning]
[birds tweeting]
[doleful piano melody playing]
[Ruth] Leviathan.
Kraken.
[creature growling]
[Ruth] Mermaids.
[distant screeching]
Think about it. Dad.
80% of the ocean floor is unexplored.
What if these things aren't
from outer space?
What if these tales of sea creatures
are real?
What if that's why
they can control the rain?
They're not conquering our world.
This is their world.
It's their home.
No. this is our home.
and you're safe here.
I promise.
If you say so.
What...
Why don't you... take a break from this?
This...
Go do something useful.
Okay.
[Ruth chuckles softly]
[Ann] Look at this.
Everything's dying.
Salt water. Ruthie was right.
That thing came in here
and poisoned all the soil.
It's the same with the drinking water.
We can't use any of it.
So that's it. then.
They starve us out like everyone else.
[Jason] Ann.
[ferret chittering]
[screeching]
-[Ann] They don't want us here. Jason.
-[Jason] That's great.
But where are we supposed to go?
We have all new tarps for collecting dew.
so we'll do that.
-We'll replant. We'll start over.
-You just said it yourself.
-We don't have water.
-It's not raining now.
-But it'll rain again.
-You have no idea.
-[Ruth] This wasn't meant for you. Hey.
-[Ann] We cannot replant.
You're too small to be in that.
[Ann] What is it you keep telling us?
Three minutes without air.
Three days without water.
Three weeks without food.
We have three days
before we die with no water.
It's not gonna come to that.
We'll have enough water to survive.
Just a little less than we used to.
I'll work it out.
What happens when that thing
comes back here? What then?
I don't know. Ann! I don't know!
What should I do? Shoot it?
Open your eyes. You think
we're still alive because of you?
We're still alive
because of a crack in the chimney.
We're not better than anyone else
who died. We're just luckier!
If we don't find a way out of this house.
we will die. and you know that!
[tense music droning]
-[squeaks]
-[screams]
-[Ruth] Oh my God. I was trying to help.
-[Jason] What is this?
I don't know what happened.
I... I'm so sorry.
I was trying to help. I didn't mean to...
-Is it bad?
-[Graham] Ruth. are you okay?
-Are you okay?
-[screeching]
-[Ann] Ruth.
-No! Don't kill it.
-[Graham] What is going on?
-Wait. Let's get this cleaned up.
-[Graham] Hey. what's going on?
-[Ruth] I don't know. I'm sorry.
-[Graham] Dad. is she gonna be okay?
-[Jason] Yeah.
[music turns somber]
[Ann] She's burning up.
The infection is spreading.
Her fever won't break.
We have to do something.
This is the last of our water.
She needs it.
-[coughs]
-Hey.
Easy.
We need antibiotics.
[engine revs]
[yelling]
-[yelling]
-[tires screeching]
[yelling]
[glass smashing]
[Ann. muffled] Jason!
Jason! Jason!
[Jason panting]
[Ann. muffled] Jason!
Graham! Help!
Come on. Come on.
Cracks. The cracks.
[hopeful orchestral music playing]
What are you doing?
[Jason grunts]
[Jason] The house is sinking.
Look at that. Look. The crack.
Jason!
[Jason] The barrier isn't deep.
-See?
-Jason. talk to me.
-[Ann] What do you see?
-It shifted.
-[Ann] Jason.
-Let me try.
-[Ann] What?
I can find a way out.
[Ann] Stop. Hey.
[Jason] Yes. it's deeper. There.
Look at me. Look at me. Jason.
-No. You listen to me.
-That's enough.
You said the house was sinking.
-Stop.
-Remember?
-Stop for a second.
-Maybe something else is shifting.
-You need to take a breath.
-Like the cracks in the chimney.
I have to try and find it. Find it.
Find what?
-See?
-See what?
See? Follow the crack.
-The crack is our escape.
-[Ann] No!
We have to follow the cracks.
I just have to find where the crack goes.
[Ann] What are you doing? Stop.
-Stop it. Jason!
-[Jason] I can do it!
Stop! Let me try!
I have to!
[Ann] That's enough!
Enough!
-You have to...
-No!
-[Jason yelling]
-[Ann] Stop!
[Ann groans]
It went through.
Stand back! Stand back!
Help me.
Here.
[music fades out]
-Where does it go?
-[Jason] It leads to the main sewer pipe.
The whole neighborhood is connected.
The Richardsons.
He's the dentist.
-He has antibiotics.
-Yeah.
-I just have to get in here.
-[Ann] You won't fit.
-I just have to make this bigger.
-Jason. the pipe's metal.
-I have to try.
-We don't have time. We don't have time.
I can fit now.
No. No. no. no.
This one is me.
This one's me.
[bleeps]
-[Ann] Testing. testing.
-Loud and clear.
[Jason] You know what I was thinking?
That "never put your wife down the toilet"
should have been one of my wedding vows.
It's a little late for that.
Don't you think?
Be careful. please.
I will.
And I'm bringing back medicine
for our baby.
Okay.
-[exhales deeply]
-Go.
Ready.
[eerie music droning]
Ann. can you see anything?
Nothing.
I'm gonna keep going.
[panting]
-[rats squeaking]
-[Ann yelps]
Wait.
There's a loose brick.
Okay. Ann. you should come back.
Come back.
[grunting]
[suspenseful string music playing]
-[Graham] Mom?
-Ann? Ann?
-No. Please. no.
-Mom. can you hear me?
Oh no. oh no.
Mom! Mom. come back!
Ann!
[Ann's speech distorted through device]
Dad! Come here right now!
Hurry up! Dad. come here.
Look. look. Come here. Hurry up.
-Look. Look. She made it.
-[Ann] Can you hear me? Hello?
-Hey. can you hear me?
-[music fades out]
-Yeah.
-Mom. Mom. are you okay?
Yeah. I'm okay.
It's Mrs. Richardson.
The tide came in?
It's like the whole house was flooded
for years.
We've run out of time. babe.
-[Graham] Mom. it's starting to rain.
-[Jason] Ann. it's raining.
Ann. find it and get out now!
I'm not leaving without it.
[Jason] It's too late.
Ann! The rain is here.
[Ann] Hold on.
Mr. Richardson?
Uh! Yes!
-[Jason] What?
-Yes.
Okay. Okay.
Clindacyclin.
-Azithromycin.
-[Graham] What is that?
-[Jason] Antibiotics.
-Tetracycline.
-[Graham] Antibiotics!
-Penicillin.
[Jason] Okay. Ann. run! Run!
-Look!
-[Jason] Get out of there! Now! Come on!
-Go! Come on!
-Go!
-[Ann] Look! I got it!
-[Jason] Go! Go now! Go!
[creature growling wetly]
[growling continues]
[chilling music playing]
[Ann] Ah. no.
[creature growling]
[music fades out]
[creature screeching]
-[Ann screaming]
-[chilling music resumes]
[panting]
[Ann grunting]
I'm down here!
I'm here! Come on.
Throw me the silk! Bring me up now!
[Jason] Here. grab it.
[creature growling]
[Ann screaming]
You got this.
[creature growling]
[growling]
[grunts]
Here you go. Okay.
Open your mouth. Here you go.
We got the meds. okay?
Open and take it. Okay. open the water.
Good. There you go.
These should kick in fast.
You're gonna be okay.
That's my girl. Come on.
Okay.
Ann. where's the gun?
I lost it.
It is going to be coming for us now.
It doesn't know how many of us there are.
You take the kids to the attic
and hide.
I'll stay here.
And. Ann.
no matter what you hear.
please
don't come out until the rain stops.
-You're giving up.
-This is the opposite of giving up. I'm...
You are going to live. All of you.
And you're gonna live for me.
This isn't living. surviving.
It's just not enough anymore.
We know that they can open that door.
and if they can come in.
then we can get out.
We'll fight them if we have to.
We can't fight them.
You don't know what you're talking about.
If there's even the slightest chance
that we can escape.
I'm taking that chance.
He's right.
Our family is breaking apart
trying to survive.
There's no life left here for us.
We have to try.
We have to escape. no matter the cost.
Okay. We'll do it together.
and we use what we have.
What do we have?
Our house.
-[purposeful music playing]
-[Jason] Open up the windows.
We're done hiding.
We're gonna let them come in.
[Ann] We will do whatever it takes
to get out of here.
[thunder crashing]
Hey. Can you take this?
[Jason] Now we are going to trap them.
Graham. you'll track the creature.
Ruth. you cast the line.
Ann. you lure it to me.
and I'll set the hook.
We'll reel it in. then make our escape.
[Ann] They trapped us in here.
thinking it would kill us.
Today is our last day in this house.
[Jason] Let's go fishing.
[music fades out]
Be safe.
[wind howling]
[creature growling]
[Jason yells]
[Graham] Ah! Ah!
[Ruth yells]
[grunting]
-[sinister music playing]
-[Ann gasping]
Ah! Ah!
-[Ruth coughing]
-[Ann] Ruth!
-Are you okay?
-[Ruth] Yeah!
[Ruth] Graham!
[Graham groaning]
Where's Dad?
-[Ann] Jason!
-[Jason] I'm okay!
[Ann groans]
Ah!
[creature roars]
It's here!
[Graham] Where's it coming from?
[Ann] It's gone!
Come on.
[creature growling]
[Ruth] It got inside!
[Graham] Mom. hide! It's in the house!
Dad! It's coming towards you!
[frantic string music playing]
[creature growling]
Where are you?
I don't have a shot!
Ann! Light it up!
Light it up now!
[creature gurgling]
[Ann grunting]
[creature growling]
It's coming back!
[Ann] Come on.
[creature screeching]
Ah! Ah! Ah!
[Jason] Gotcha.
-Ah!
-[Graham] Dad!
-Dad!
-No!
[Jason yells]
[creature bellowing]
-Jason!
-[Graham] Dad!
[Ann] Jason!
Ah! Ah!
We gotta go! Come on!
Come on. Dad! Come on!
[Ann] Hurry up! Let's go! Let's go!
-[dramatic brass chord]
-[music fades out]
The water is rising too fast!
We have to get to the attic!
Where's the harpoon?
I missed. It's in the kitchen.
Forget it. Let's go!
[Graham] I can get it!
I'll meet you up there.
Go.
[water gurgling]
[inhales deeply]
[suspenseful percussive music playing]
[grunts]
[creature growling]
[creature roaring]
-[creature growling]
-[suspenseful music building]
[gasps]
[screaming]
[Ann] Watch out!
[Ann] Hurry! Go!
-[Ann] Hurry!
-[Jason] Go!
[Ruth] Come on! Go!
-Come on!
-[Jason] Run!
[Ann] Come on!
[Graham] Ruth. try the window. Dad!
[Ann] Come on! Push!
-Come on!
-[Graham] The hook. the hook!
[Jason] Come on. let's go.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
We have nowhere to go.
-You get this loaded!
-[Graham] Okay.
Quick!
[Graham] There you go.
-Ah!
-[Jason] Ah!
[panting]
Ruth. cast the line!
We need to find the silk!
It's too dark!
Just stay together!
Breathe! Take a deep breath!
-[creature roaring]
-[piano keys clunk]
[determined orchestral music playing]
[creature screeching]
[roaring]
[screeches]
[all gasping]
[Graham] I can't hold on!
[Ann] Graham!
[Jason yelling]
Go! Hurry!
[creature wailing]
[roaring]
[Jason grunting]
Open the door. or I'm gonna gut you!
[creature bellowing forlornly]
Jason. the house is coming down!
Let us out!
[Ann strains] It's not opening.
Open the door!
Dad. stop!
If you kill it. we'll never get out!
[melancholy piano music playing]
I tried to tell you.
but the one I saw seemed nice.
-It's not nice.
-[Ruth] She's trying to communicate.
-This is their home.
-No. this is our home.
[music fades out]
I have one job only.
which is to keep all of you guys alive.
This is not just your problem.
We survive because I fight for us.
You bought a gun?
What do we do when that thing comes back?
I don't know! Shoot it?
No. no. no! Don't kill it!
[creature squelches]
[creature grunting softly]
[creature whimpering wetly]
[creature grunting]
[apprehensive music playing]
[creature growling]
[roaring]
-[metallic click]
-[creaking]
[gasping]
[creature grunts wetly]
[creatures growling]
[Ruth] Mom. Dad?!
[Ann] It's okay.
[creatures squelching]
[creature whining]
[bellows]
[serene string music playing]
[hopeful piano playing]
Ruth!
[sweet string melody playing]
[Ann] Ruth!
Stop!
[Ruth laughing]
[Ann] Ruth! Ruth. stop!
[gulls cawing]
[woman] Everyone remembers where they were
the day the rain stopped.
[distant bellowing]
It was a Tuesday. not quite summer.
[light. determined music playing]
For the first time in years.
my family felt hope.
In the end. an act of mercy set us free.
We showed it to them.
and they showed it to us.
We never saw them again.
but we think they're still out there.
After all. it's their home too.
Where to?
Sheet the mainsail!
[woman] My parents. my brother. and I
set off in search of a new home.
For many years.
we felt like we were alone.
After the rain.
we knew we didn't have to be.
[over radio] Can anybody hear me?
Are there any other survivors out there?
[distorted voice] Hello?
[tense orchestral music playing]
[music fades]
[creature growls]
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today